ESMA ERDEM

Bangor, ME | 207-412-8936 | esmaerdem94@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Software Engineer with entry-level experience in software development, Python and Javascript. Equipped with proven problem-solving and analytical thinking skills gained through Astronautical Engineering with High Honors Degree and a track record of success in team leadership and effective communication in my previous role as a sales manager. Excited to combine my technical skills and business acumen to drive impactful results and grow with the company.

SKILLS

Web Development, JavaScript, AJAX, Git, SQL, PostgreSQL, Python, Flask, Node.js, Express, Jasmine, Jest

PROJECTS

Wicked Acadia Wicked Acadia Live GitHub Repo

Apr 2023 - May 2023

- Developed a comprehensive platform to assist nature enthusiasts in planning visits to Acadia National Park. Utilized a tech stack including Python, Flask, JavaScript, Postgres, and Jinja templates.
- Integrated user-friendly features include user sign-up, secure login, and favorites/bookmarks functionality.
- Implemented advanced security practices, including sensitive information hashing and password reset via email.
- Designed an efficient Restful API to interface between the front-end and database, caching external API data storage.
- Employed Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) techniques to architect and establish relational database models.
- Embraced object-oriented programming principles to enhance code reusability and maintainability.
- Ensured the creation of extensive documentation and rigorous unit testing, including Flask integration tests, to achieve bug-free and maintainable code.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Springboard | Online

Current

Software Engineering Certification

- Key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Included 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of in-depth portfolio projects.
- Honed skills in Data Structures, and Algorithms, Web Development, JavaScript, AJAX, Git, SQL, PostgreSQL, Python, Flask, Node.js, Express.

Turkish Aeronautical Association University | Ankara, Turkiye

July 2017

BS Astronautical Engineering, 3.29

- Relevant Coursework: Algorithmic Computer Programming, Linear Algebra, Computational Methods
- Acquired advanced algorithmic and computational skills through rigorous coursework and an immersive internship experience. Self-taught Matlab and expertly applied these skills to successfully complete internship projects and subsequent coursework.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Student, Springboard Software Engineering | Remote

Jan 2023 - Current

- Gaining a deep understanding of software development, with a focus on web application architecture and functionality.
- Applying clean and concise programming practices, prioritizing collaborative code readability.
- Emphasizing documentation and rigorous testing for bug-free, maintainable code.
- Implementing diverse hands-on projects, including data structures and web applications using Flask and Express.
- Proficiently managing relational databases through SQL and enhancing functionality with API integration.

Sales Manager, Cool As A Moose | Provincetown, MA

Jan 2019 - Sept 2022

- Managed successful retail/gift shop, overseeing operations, and leading a team. Achieved 70% revenue growth in the
 first year through effective customer service and strategic planning.
- Conducted regular health checks on the point-of-sale system and analyzed inventory data using retail star software.
- Developed and executed successful marketing campaigns, increasing brand visibility and community engagement.
- Coached and trained new hires across multiple locations on operations, customer service, and leadership.